Welcome to the eLearning session, Getting
欢迎来到 elearning 课程
Started with Ensemble and HL7.
Ensemble 和 HL7 入门
Ensemble supports a wide range of integration functionality
Ensemble 支持的集成功能和协议范围非常广
and protocols, but this session explains the basic components
但在这个课程里，我们主要讲解一些基本的组件
of an Ensemble solution for someone using Ensemble
以及如何使用 Ensemble
as an HL7 interface engine.
作为 HL7 接口引擎的一些解决方案
An Ensemble solution is known as a Production.
就大家所知而言，Production 为 Ensemble 的解决方案
A Production can be made up of many components that
一个 Production 可有很多组件组成
handle inbound and outbound connections
处理入口和出口的连接
and control the flow of information between them.
以及控制出入口间的信息流
The Production is created once and configuration items
一个 Production被生成，组件和配置项
are added to complete
the solution.
将被加入来完成这个解决方案
A large Production may have hundreds of configuration
一个大的 Production 也许会有数百个配置组件
items, but the
examples here will have
为了方便阐述
a small number for clarity.
这里所给的例子比较小
The inbound connection points are known as Business Services
入口的连接称之为 Business Services
These handle the technology used for a connection,
其利用如下的技术进行连接
such as TCP/IP, flat files, SOAP, FTP, or HTTP.
比如 TCP/IP,文本文件，SOAP, FTP,或者 HTTP
For some formats, such as HL7, these
又如一些格式，比如 HL7,这些
are pre-built components that just
预建的组件
have to be configured with the appropriate parameters
只需要进行适当的参数配置
such as the port
number for TCP/IP
比如对于 TCP/IP 的端口
or the path and
name for flat files.
或者文本文件的路径和文件名
The outbound connections are
known as Business Operations.
出口的连接称之为 Business Operations
Like Business Services, they're
added using the configuration
如同 Business Service, 他们由配置向导加入
wizards.
The Business Services
and Business Operations
Business Service 和 Business Operation
handle everything to
do with the connection,
处理所有关于连接的事项
such as initial connection,
retries, timeouts, and framing,
比如初始化连接，重试，超时，分帧
as well as the
actual wire protocol.
以及连线实际的协议
This is kept separate
from any logic to route
将这些与消息的路由以及转换逻辑
or transform the message.
分离开来
With HL7, a Business Service
typically sends a message
在 HL7 中，一个 Business Service 通常发送消息
to a Message Router.
到消息路由
Normally, a separate
Message Router
通常，一个独立的消息路由
is used for each
Business Service,
运用到每个 Business Service
although this is not necessary.
虽然这不是必须的
The Message Router uses
a set of Routing Rules
消息路由利用一组路由规则
to determine where the
message must be sent
以决定消息消息要送到何处
and which Data Transformation
to call for each destination.
以及要进行怎样的装换
The Routing Rules
determine where the message
路由规则根据消息源，
is sent based on the
source and type of message
消息类型以及内容
and the content of fields
within the message.
决定消息送往何处
For example, admissions
messages might
比如，病人入院消息
be sent to one set
of applications,
可能送往某一组应用
but results might be
sent somewhere else.
但结果可能送往其他地方
You will normally want to modify
a message before sending it
通常你可能希望在发送消息到目的地前
to its destination.
对其进行修改
This is done using a
Data Transformation.
这可以由数据转换 (Data Transformation) 来完成
The graphical editor allows
you to copy segments and fields
这是一个图形化的编辑器，你可以将片断或字段
from the old message
to the new message
从旧消息复制到新消息
and make changes to
meet the requirements
根据目标要求进行转换
of the destination.
As well as the setting
where message is sent,
同时根据消息要发送到何地
the Routing Rules decide what
Data Transformation should
路由规则决定在发送前
be applied before sending it.
做什么样的数据转换。
In Ensemble, the connection
management and configuration,
在 Ensemble 连接管理和配置中
the logic for deciding where to
route a message and the logic
决定消息的路由的逻辑以及数据转换的逻辑
for transforming
message are kept
是保持分开的
separate to simplify
development and testing.
其原因是使开发和测试简单化
Additional items may be
added to the Production.
还有些其它的项目也许要添加到 Production.
For example, you might
add a bad message handler
比如，你需要加入一个坏消息的处理机制
to receive any messages
that fail validation
接受没有通过校验的消息
/************************************************************
or an alert handler
to route alerts
或者到正确接受目的的
to the right destination.
路由警报
****************************************************************/
I'm going to demonstrate
these components by building
我将从头开始创建一个 Production
a Production from scratch.
来演示这些组件
In this session, I will be
using Ensemble version 2012.1.
在这节课程中，我会用 Ensemble 的 2012.1 版本
In this version, the appearance
has changed considerably
这个版本，从外观上与以前的版本 2010.2
from the previous
version 2010.2,
有比较大的改变
making it much easier to use.
这些改变使这个版本更容易使用
Let's start with a
brand new installation
让我们从一个新的安装开始
as if we had just
installed Ensemble.
假设我们已经完成一个 Ensemble 的安装
Before you can configure
your first connections,
在你配置第一个连接前，
you have to create a Production.
你必须先创建一个 Production
This is a collection
of all the interfaces
这是组成你所有 HL7 路由方案的
that make up your
HL7 routing solution,
接口的集合
and you only create it once.
并且你只要创建一次。
To create a new
Production, we're
为了创建一个新的 Production
going to go to the
Management Portal
我们需要进入到管理门户
and click on the Ensemble tab.
点击 Ensemble 标签
We then need to choose
our Namespace and an area
然后我们需要选择一个 Namespace
to work in.
作为一个工作区
We'll choose ENSDEMO.
我们会选 ENSDEMO
Then we're going to go
to List, Productions.
然后我们到 Productions 的列表
In this list, we see a
list of sample Productions
在列表中，我们可以看到一列例子 Productions
that have already
been created for us.
这是已经为我们创建好的
To create a new
Production, we're
为了创建一个新的，我们只要
simply going to click the
New button up at the top.
简单的点击在顶部的新建(New) 按钮
I'm going to create a Production
called MyHospital.HL7Engine.
我将要创建 MyHospital.HL7Engine 的 Production
By clicking on the
HL7 radio button,
点击 HL7 的单选按钮
I will get a few
components pre-built for me
我可看到一些预制的组件
that will be used for later.
我会在以后用到
A generic Production has
no component to start.
一个通用的 Production 在一开始没有任何组件
Let's first create
a Production Name.
首先我们给 Production 起一个名字
I'm going to enter a new name.
我将要输入一个新的名字
And my package is going
to be called MyHospital.
至于我的包名，我会起为 MyHospital
And my Production Name
is going to be HL7Engine.
我给 Production 起名为 HL7Engine
I can optionally
also give myself
我也可以输入一些描述性的东西
a description to explain what
this Production is going to do.
解释这个 Production 会做什么 (可选)
When I have all those fields
filled out, I can click OK.
当填完这些字段后，我点击 OK.
You can see Business Service
or inbound connections
在左侧，你可以看到 Business Service 或则入口连接
on the left, Business Operations
or outbound connections
在右边有 Business Operation 或出口连接
on the right, and Business
Processes or Routing Engines
以及 Business Process 或者规则引擎 (Routine Engine)
in the middle.
在中间
I'm going to start the
Production even though it
我现在启动 Production
doesn't do anything yet.
虽然它目前什么也没有做
I'm going to create two inbound
and two outbound connections
我将创建两个入口连接和一个出口连接
in no particular order.
不需要按特定次序创建
First, I know I want to
send messages over TCP/IP
首先，我要通过 TCP/IP 发送消息
to the lab system.
到检验系统
So although I have some Business
Operations already created,
虽然，我已经创建了一些 Business Operations
I'm going to create
a new Business
我还是要从头开始创建一个
Operation from scratch.
Business Operation
First, I know I want to
send messages over TCP/IP
首先，我知道我需要通过 TCP/IP
to the lab system.
发送消息到检验系统。
So even though I already
have Business Operations
虽然，我已经创建了一些 Business Operations
in my Production, I'm going to
create a new Business Operation
我还是要从头开始创建一个 Business Operation
from scratch by clicking on the
plus sign next to Operations.
点击 Operation 边上的加号
The wizard leads me
through the key choices.
创建向导会指引我输入一些关键选项
First, I want to choose
that it's an HL7 output.
首先，我要选择这是一个 HL7 输出
So I'm going to
choose the HL7 tab.
所以，我会选择 HL7 标签
And then I'm going
to choose TCP,
然后，我选择 TCP
because I know I want it
to be a TCP connection.
因为我知道我需要的是一个 TCP 连接
I can then choose a name.
我可以选一个名字
I'm going to choose
To_Lab, because it's
我将要选 To_Lab, 因为这个名字
fairly unambiguous.
相当明确
I can also supply an IP
address and port number now,
现在我也可以提供 IP 地址以及端口号
or I could leave it to
be configured later.
我也可以空着，以后配置。
I've already set
up an application
我已经配置了一个应用
that will be sending messages
over a TCP connection.
其会通过 TCP 连接发送消息
So we'll use the IP
address and port number
所以我们会用我已知的
that I already know.
IP 地址和端口号
And then I can
select Enable Now,
然后我选择 "Enable Now"
because I want to
enable it right now.
因为我要它马上启用
I also know I want to send flat
files to the billing system,
我还需要发送一个文本文件到一个计费西贡/////////////////////////system
so I'll do the same thing
again, but this time, I
我会做为此做同样的事情，但这次
will say To_Billing and make
it a file Business Operation.
我会用一个文件的 Business Operation,起名为 To_Billing
Notice we have a different
set of questions here.
注意到，在这里，我们会有一组不同的配置
As for a file,
Business Operation,
对于文件型的 Business Operation
we have different
options on what
我们有两个不同的选项
we're going to want to fill out,
for example, File Path and File
我们会要一个文件出口，比如文件的路径和
Name.
文件名
Notice my %F and %Q
actually do mean something.
注意到，我用了 %F 和 %Q，实际上是有含义的
%F means we're going to use
the same name as was used
%F 意味着我们会用和入口同样的文件名
on the inbound, and %Q
means to add a timestamp.
%Q 表明我们会加上时间戳
To simplify this, I'm going
to just do billing.txt.
为简便起见，我们只用 billing.txt 文件。
Now for the input.
作为输入。
I know that I will receive
messages from a text
我知道会我们会从一个应用 ApplicactionX
file put there by ApplicationX.
收到一个文本文件
So using the new
Business Service wizard,
所以在使用 Business Service 向导的时候
I can choose File and specify
the File Path and File Name.
我会选择 File 并指定文件路径和文件名
To create a new
Business Service,
创建一个新的 Business Service,
I'm going to use the plus sign
next to Business Services.
我将用 Business Services 边上的加号。
Then like the
Business Operation,
然后如同 Buiness Operation 那样，
I'm also going to choose
HL7 input and choose File.
我将选择 HL7 输入并选择 File 类型
The Name I'm going to choose
for my HL7 Business Service
至于我的 HL7 Business Service 命名，
is going to be
From_ApplicationX.
我打算起为,From_ApplicationX
And I will specify a File
Path and File Name also
同时在向导中，我也会指定
in this wizard.
文件路径和文件名
Notice the star means that I'm
going to take anything that
注意到，在 “*" 号意味着，我会选取所有
ends with ".txt".
".txt" 为结尾的文件
I will also tell Ensemble
what version of messages
我还会告诉 Ensemble，在这个连接上
will be received
over this connection.
将要收到的消息版本
You can see we support
all the standard versions.
你可以看到我们支持所有标准版本。
And if you have to find
custom message schemas,
你也会发现在下拉框中有
they will be included
in the drop down.
用户自定义的 schema
The wizard also
gives you the option
向导也提供其它选项
to select an existing Routing
Engine or create a new one.
选用一个已经存在的路由引擎或是新建一个
In most cases, it will want
a Routing Engine dedicated
对于大多数例子，每一个 Business Service
to each Business Service.
有个专属的路由引擎
Make sure it's enabled.
启用
And now we have to find
the Business Service.
现在我们需要查找这个 Business Service
We can click OK,
because this is just
我们可以点击 OK， 因为这只是
going to create our
new message router.
创建我们新的消息路由。
Notice we get a
From_ApplicationX.
注意到，在 From_ApplicationX 有个点，
If we click on the
dot next to the name,
如果我们点击这个点，
it will show us the connections.
它会显示出一连接线。
And From_ApplicationX is
going to send the message
显示出 From_ApplicationX 将会发送消息
to From_ApplicationX_Router.
到 From_ApplicationX_Router.
So far, we have created
one inbound and two
到目前为止，我们创建了
outbound connections.
一个入口和两个出口连接。
We have created
a Routing Engine,
我们还创建了一个路由引擎，
and the inbound
connection has been
同时入口连接配置成
configured to send all messages
to this new Routing Engine.
发送所有消息到路由引擎。
When the Routing
Engine was created,
当创建路由引擎时，
a Routing Rules set
was also created.
一组路由规则也会被创建。
But so far, the Routing
Rules are empty,
但是，目前为止，路由规则是空的。
so the message still
won't go anywhere.
所以消息不会被发送出去。
The next step is
to add the Routing
下一步，需要加入路由规则
Rules that determine where
the message should be sent.
以决定消息要送到哪里。
Let's take a look at
the Routing Rules.
让我们看一下路由规则。
We're going to click on
From_ApplicationX_Router.
我们选中 From_ApplicationX_Router.
And in the settings over
here on the right hand side,
在设置的右手边，
you'll notice a setting
called Business Rule Name.
你会注意到 Business Rule Name 的设置。
If I click on the
magnifying glass,
如果你点击那个放大镜，
my rule set will
appear up top here.
我的规则组就会在头部显示出来。
I can see here that I have
a rule set with one rule,
我可以看规则组中只有一条规则，
but nothing is sent anywhere.
但是没有发送消息去任何地方
A Routing Rule has
some constraints
一个路由规则有一些约束条件
on the type and
source of the message
在消息类型和消息源上
and then conditions on the
content of the message.
然后再消息内容上设置条件
If these evaluate to true,
the actions are performed.
如果条件评定为真，那么执行动作。
Let's first create a
rule where we route based
让我们先来创建一条规则，
on coming From_ApplicationX,
being message type ADT_A01,
从 From_AppliationX 进来的消息类型为 ADT_A01，
schema of 2.5.
schema 为 2.5
To edit this rule, I'm going to
double click on "constraint".
编辑其为真，我双击 "constraint"
I can choose the Source.
我可以选数据源。
In our case, we want
to choose ApplicationX.
在我们这个例子里，我选 ApplicationX
Note the Message Type is
referred to here as Document
注意，消息的类型指的是文档
Name.
名字
Once we've added this rule,
we then want to add a target
当我们加入这条规则，然后我们加入目标
and send it someplace.
发送其到某地。
So I'm going to add the plus.
所以我添加一个加号
I'm going to do "when".
我选中 "when"
My condition will
always be true.
我的条件是永远为真
And then I want to
send it to a target.
然后，我要发送其道目的地。
And I want to send
this to my To_Billing.
我要将其发送到我的 To_Billing
I can also choose multiple
configuration items
我也可以选则多个目的地，
to send it two at a time.
一次发送它到两个地方。
So for example, if I want
to send it to both of these,
比如，如果我要发送到这两个地方，
I can Select both
of those boxes.
我可选中这两个选框。
For now, I'm just going
to choose To_Billing.
目前，我只选择 To_Billing.
Now my next rule, I want
to send it to To_Lab.
现在，我要建下一个规则，我要发送它去 To_Lab.
So I'm going to
add another rule.
所以我会添加另一条规则。
Click on rule set.
点击规则组。
Add another rule.
加入另一条规则
And I want the second
rule to match all items
我想要这第二条规则如果匹配所有的项目
and then send a
message to To_Lab.
会发送消息到 To_Lab.
Now we have two destinations.
现在我们有两个目的地。
We optionally can also include
Data Transformations in a rule
在规则中，我们也可以加入数据转换 (可选）
as well.
You'll notice this empty
box labeled Transform.
你会之意到有个标签为 "Transform" 的空框。
If the rule was true
and there's a return,
如果规则为真，然后返回，
the rules set will exit.
那么会退出规则组。
Notice this return right here.
注意到，就在此返回。
And if the rule is
false, the Rule Engine
如果规则判定为假，那么规则引擎
moves onto the next
rule and the rule set,
会移到规则组的下一条规则，
and therefore, will
evaluate rule two,
然后检验规则二，
if we omitted our return, then
if we matched our first rule,
如果我们略去我们的返回，那么当第一个规则为真，
it will continue on and also
try to match the second rule.
会继续去匹配第二个规则。
Let's make sure to
save our Routing Rule
我们确认我们保存了路由规则
and go back to our
configuration page.
然后回到我们的配置页面。
Now we're ready to put a file
in and see how this works.
现在我们已经准备好放入文件，并察看他是如何工作的。
Notice From_ApplicationX
has a red dot next it.
注意到，From_ApplicationX 边上有个红点。
This means that Ensemble
recognizes that component
这意味着，Ensemble 注意到
as having an error.
这个组件有错误发生。
I know from setting this up that
although I had specified a File
我知道在设置的时候，虽然我已经指定了
Path, I did not actually create
the File Path on my system.
文件路径，但是我没有真正地在我的系统里创建这路径。
I need to make sure to go
and do that before I can
在这文件夹下放入文件前，
place a file in that folder.
我要确认创建了路径。
I have some sample files
that I'm already using,
我有一些例子文件
so I can use one of
those message sets.
I'm going to paste that file,
that text file into my folder.
我会将这文件粘贴到我的文件夹
And notice, without
doing anything,
然后注意到，不要做任何事情，
Ensemble immediately
takes that file in.
Ensemble 立即取走了这些文件。
I can then go back to my front
page of my Management Portal,
我可以回到管理门户的首页，
and I can view the messages
directly in Ensemble.
然后我可以在 Ensemble 中直接察看消息。
To do so, I'm going
to do View, Messages.
为此，我们选择 "View","Message"
And I can see here that
we have one message that
我们可以看到我们有一条消息
came through From_ApplicationX
and went directly
来自于 From-ApplicationX 并且直接
to From_ApplicationX_Router.
发送到 From_ApplicationX_Router.
If I select that message,
over on the right hand side,
如果我选中这消息，在右手边，
I can view the contents.
我可以看消息的内容。
And I can also see
the Trace or the Path
并且，我也可以看这消息
that that message took.
经由的的跟踪和路径
We can see here it
went From_ApplicationX
我们在此可以看到消息从 From_ApplicationX
to From_ApplicationX_Router
and then was routed
到 From_ApplicationX_Router 以及路由
to To_Lab Business Operation.
到 To_Lab Business Operation。
Now let's review what we did.
现在我们回顾一下我们所做的事情。
We created two
outbound connections
我们创建了两个出口连接
or Business Operations.
或者说 Business Operations.
We then created one inbound
connection or Business Service.
然后我们创建了一个入口连接，或者说 Business Service.
We also created a
Message Router where
我们也创建了一个消息路由，在此
we were able to edit
our Routing Rules
我们可以编辑我们的路由规则
and route to both
Business Operations
以及根据一组条件，
based on a set of criteria.
路由到两个 Business Operations
We hope this helped
in learning how
我们希望只能帮助大家学习如何
to set up a basic Production.
配置一个基本的 Production。
Thank you for
watching, and we hoped
感谢您的收看，我们也希望
this helps you learn
the basics of Ensemble.
这能帮助大家学习基本的 Ensemble